A Guide to the Harry Downing Temple. Jr., Papers, 1872-2004
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Harry Downing Temple Jr., Papers, 1872-2004 (bulk, 1930-2001)
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Temple, Harry Downing
Ms1988-039
46.5 Cubic Feet 49 boxes, 3 oversize folders
The Harry Downing Temple, Jr., Papers contains materials related to Temple's personal life, interest in heraldry and insignia, and his research and publications on the Virginia Tech Corps of Cadets. Materials date from about 1872 to 2004.
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Technical Access
Please note: This collection includes recordings of lectures on 7mm reel-to-reel. Special Collections and University Archives has an appropriate audio player and recordings can be listened to in the the reading room.
Acquisition Information
The manuscripts and photographs for The Bugle's Echo were donated in 1998. Additional materials were donated prior to 2004 and in 2011.
Biographical Note
Harry Downing Temple was born in Elizabeth City County (now Hampton), Virginia, on October 24, 1911, and reared in Petersburg, Virginia. He attended Virginia Polytechnic Institute as a member of the Corps of Cadets from 1930 to 1934, and graduated with a bachelor of science degree in industrial engineering. He served as a professional officer of the U.S. Army and participated in World War II and the Korean War, rising to the rank of Colonel. From 1961 to 1966 he headed the Army's Institute of Heraldry, and designed the Presidential Medal of Freedom. He retired from the Army in 1966. Colonel Temple died in 2004.
Temple began his research for a book about the Virginia Tech Corps of Cadets in the mid-1970s, and retired to Blacksburg, Virginia, in 1988, to be closer to the archival materials necessary for his research. Volume I of The Bugle's Echo, which chronicle's the years between 1872 and 1900, was published by the Virginia Tech Corps of Cadets Alumni, Inc., in 1996. Volume II, with details about the years between 1900 and 1912, was published in 1998. Volume III covers 1912-1920; Volume IV covers 1920-1926; Volume V covers 1926-1930; the final volume, Volume VI, covers the Corps from 1930 to 1934.
Scope and Content
The Harry Downing Temple, Jr., Papers contains materials related to Temple's personal life, interest in heraldry and insignia, and his research and publications on the Virginia Tech Corps of Cadets. Materials date from about 1872 to 2004.
The majority of the collection is comprised of research for The Bugle's Echo, including handwritten manuscripts, drafts, copies of research material, and extensive collection of photographs. Most of the research materials are photocopies from the Bugle, Techgram, and the Collegiate Times. As part of his research on Virginia Tech, Col. Temple collected a few original letters and memorabilia from other cadets. This collection houses a few of these letters and reminisces from the early years of Virginia Tech's history.
The other materials in the collection stem largely from Colonel. Temple's interest in the military and heraldry. The collection contains materials ranging from battle maps of Europe from the Napoleonic Wars to World War II, to heraldric drawings made by Temple or audio recordings of lectures he attended. Also included are various publications about heraldry and the military that Temple accumulated over his lifetime.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in seven series. Series I-V are arranged in alphabetical order. Within Series VI, research files are classified by date. Series VII is arranged by volume of The Bugle's Echo with which the materials are associated.
Series I, Biographical material contains materials pertinant to Colonel Temple's life, like awards and certificates, and praise for The Bugle's Echo. Series II contains a large collection of heraldric drawings and research which Colonel Temple gathered or drew himself over his lifetime. Series III is comprised of Colonel Temple's research on Virginia Tech, much of which overlap with Colonel Temple's research for his books. Series IV contains research materials largely related to the military.
Series V, VI, and VIII contain materials directly related to Colonel Temple's work on The Bugle's Echo. Handwritten manuscripts, research for future editions, and photographs, respectively, make up these series. Please note: Boxes of photographs, negatives, and slides are denoted with Boxes 1P-15P.
Related Materials
Temple, Harry Downing, and Floyd Richard Vranian. 1996. The Bugle's Echo: A Chronology of Cadet Life at the Military College at Blacksburg, Virginia, the Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and the Virginia Polytechnic Institute. [Blacksburg, Va.]: Virginia Tech Corps of Cadets Alumni. Call number: LD5655 .T46 1996
Rights Statements for Archival Description
The guide to the Harry Downing Temple, Jr., Papers by Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, is licensed under a CC0 (https://creativecommons.org/share-your-work/public-domain/cc0/).
Index Terms
Subjects:
Heraldry; University Archives; University History; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Corps of Cadets
Genre and Form Terms:
Photographs
Contents List
- Series I: Biographical Material, 1930-2004
  - Army - Seventh Corps, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Army Commission Forms, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Army Course Papers, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Army Field Exercise at Fort Benning, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Article, "The Art of Arms," New River Current, 1989 (Folder 1)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1934-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5, Folder 1)
  - The Blast, ROTC Camp newsletter, 1930 (Folder 1)
  - Certificate for Promotion to Colonel, 1963 (Folder 1)
  - Class Reunions, 1959-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Command and General Staff College Diploma, 1950 (Folder 1)
  - Commencement Programs, 1931, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1994-2003 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Thank you's for personal Copies of Bugle's Echo, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Genealogy of Colonel Temple's family, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Honors for Bugle's Echo, 1995-2004 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - In Memoriam, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Other Biographical Material, 1930-2001 (Folder 1, Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Petersburg High School, Class of 1931 Reunion, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Pins, Medals, and Memorabilia, n.d. (Box 7)
  - "Preparation of Map Exercises", 1950 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Print, Virginia Capitol Building (Folder 1)
  - Uniform jackets, n.d. (Box 34)
    Separated Materials
    These items are not housed with the Harry Downing Temple, Jr., Papers. They are located in the Specialc Collections and University Archives textile collection.
  - US Army Travel Orders, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Vocabulary Studies, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Series II: Heraldry and Insignia, 1915-2001 (bulk, 1950-1990)
  - "The Aesthetics of Design" Lecture (7mm reel), n.d. (Box 8)
  - Army Regulation 670-5: Uniform and Insignia for Male Personnel, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Army Regulation 670-30: Female Personnel, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Army Regulation 672-5-1: Awards, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "The Art and Science of Heraldry" Lectures by H. Ellis Tomlinson (10 7mm reels), 1965 (Box 10, Box 11)
  - College of Arms Photograph, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Conference Lectures Given at by John Philip Brooke Little, (5 7mm reels), 1964 (Box 9)
  - Creation of Corps of Cadets Coat of Arms, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Donning the Blue and Gray Slides, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Drawings of Virginia Tech Uniforms from the Early 20th Century, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Flags and Pennants (Military Specifications F-2692C), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Highty-Tighty Baldric (Corps of Cadets), 2000 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Heraldry Drawings for Churches and Organizations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Heraldry Notecards, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Heraldry Slides, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - The Heraldry Society document, 1957 (Folder 1)
  - "Lectures Given at Institute of Heraldry" by John Phillip Brooke Little (3 7mm reels), 1965 (Box 8)
  - Loose Pictures, Designs, and Drawings, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Insignia Drawings (Military) (7 folders),, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36-42)
  - Insignia Reproductions (oversize) (Folder 2)
    - Badges of the Seventh Corps, United States Army, 1898
    - 2nd Regiment Infantry, Virginia Volunteers Flag, n.d.
    - Division and Brigade Badges of the Seventh Corps, n.d.
    - Flags of the Second Division, Seventh Corps, n.d.
    - Dimensions of the Flags of the Seventh Corps, n.d.
    - Flags of the First Division, Seventh Corps, n.d.
    - Flags of the Seventh Corps, United States Army, 1898
    - Flags of the Third Division, Seventh Corps, n.d.
    - Second Regiment Virginia Volunteers Flag, n.d.
  - Miscellaneous Heraldry Notes, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - M.I.T. Heraldry, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Other Army Regulation Pamphlets (partial), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Oversize Heraldry Prints: Uniforms and Descriptions, n.d. (Folder 1)
  - Partial Publications, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Post Cards from College of Heraldry, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Postcards of Military Uniforms,, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Publications A-Coa, 1923-1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Bibliography
    "A Collection of Flags of the American Revolution, and those of the United States Army, its government, and Armed Forces," n.d.
    An Academic Costume Code and Ceremony Guide (photocopy), 1960
    "An Altar Guild Manual," 1953
    Army, Navy, Marine Corps Insignia, 1943
    "Articles by Gilbert Potter" (heraldry), n.d.
    The Bookplates of George Taylor Friend, 1963
    Carmarthenshire Studies, n.d.
    Ciencia Heraldrica O Del Blason (photocopy), n.d.
    The Coast Artillery Journal Vol 59 (photocopy), 1923
    The Coat of Arms Vol II, n.d.
  - Publications Cos-Da, 1926-1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Costume of Prelates of the Catholic Church (photocopy), 1926
    Danske Kommunevabener, 1967
  - Publications, De-Ec, 1933-1942 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    De Hallandaska Harads-Vapnen, n.d.
    Devices of Army School Distinctive Insignia (photocopy), 1942
    Ecclesiastical Heraldry - and Architects (photocopy), 1933
  - Publications Em-Fla, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Emblems of the Saints (photocopy), n.d.
    "Flags and Coats of Arms of the American Nations," n.d.
    "Flags and Coats of Arms of the American Republics," n.d.
    "Flags of the Confederate States of America," n.d.
    The Flags of the Confederate States of America (photocopy), n.d.
  - Publications Fl-He, 1926-1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    "The Flow Chart Method and Heraldic Inquiries," 1967
    "The General State Archives," 1964
    Grand Commandery Knights Templar of Virginia, 1966
    Heraldry, 1933
    "Heraldry and Iconography," n.d.
    "Heraldry and the Diocese of Virginia," 1971
    Heraldry of the Roman Catholic Church (photocopy), 1926
    "Heraldry: The Shorthand of History" (photocopy), n.d.
    "Heralds as Titles and Surnames" (photocopy), 1964
  - Publications Hi, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Historic Dress of the Clergy (photocopy), n.d.
    History of Early Christian Art (photocopy), n.d.
  - Publications I-M, 1921-1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Illustrated Chart of American Flags,n.d.
    Infantry Journal Volume XVIII, 1921
    The Law of Arms in England, n.d.
    "Le Reglement Heraldique Suedois De 1953," 1958
    "L'hermine Diversicolore Dans Le Blason Anglais" (photocopy), n.d.
    "List of Members and Register of The Heraldry Society," 1965
    "List of Members and Register of the Heraldry Society," 1971
    "List of Publications and Other Articles for Sale from the Heraldry Society," 1964
    The Medal Collector Vol. 14, 1963
    "Minor Monsters" (photocopy), n.d.
    Modern Lettering (photocopy), n.d.
    "Mongolian Symbology" (photocopy), n.d.
  - Publications O-R, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    "Ordres Equestres de la Republique de Sanit-Marin," n.d.
    The Ornaments of the Ministries (photocopy), n.d.
    Oxford and Cambridge Arms of the Colleges, n.d.
    Painted Heraldic Panels, 1955
    "Pattee, Patonce and Formee" (photocopy), n.d.
    Regimental Stripings, n.d.
    "The Riddle of A 13th Century Sword-Belt," n.d.
    "Rolls of Arms," 1951
  - Publications S-T, 1915-1964 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Seal and Arms of Pennsylvania (photocopy), n.d.
    "Seals and Other Devises in Use in the Government Printing Office," 1958
    The Seal of the United States,n.d.
    "Septieme Congress International des Sciences Genealogique et Heraldique," 1964
    Sigillogia: Being Some Account of the Great or Broad Seal of the Confederate States of America (photocopy), n.d.
    The Society of Genealogists Report, 1915
    Sonderdruck aus dem Bundesanzinger Nr 41 vom 28, 1958
    "Studies in the Heraldry of Canterbury Cathedral," 1954
    "Teutonic Knights and their Arms," n.d.
  - Publications U-Z, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Uniform and Dress of the Confederate States (photocopy), n.d.
    Uniform Insignia, n.d.
    "Walter Bellenger: Ireland King of Arms, 1467-87," 1958
    "Work of the College of Arms," n.d.
    Ye Armorie (arms, crests, and monograms), n.d.
  - Quartermaster Corps U.S. Army - Emblem Drawings, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Reserve Officer's Training Corps, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Revision of "Our Flag" Pamphlet by Department of Defense, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Seals of German Cities, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Seals of Virginia, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Spanish Heraldry, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Tampa, FL, Heraldry, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Uniform Sketches, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - United Kingdom Heraldry, 1953-1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - United Kingdom Heraldry Publications (incomplete copies), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Heraldry, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Regiment Flags and Heraldry, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Virginia Senate Coat of Arms - Newspaper Clippings, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Tech Heraldry and Insignia, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - V.M.I. Coat of Arms, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - V.P.I. File in Institute of Heraldry, U.S. Army, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - White House Executive Order 10834 - Flag of the United States, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Series III: Virginia Tech Research and History, 1882-2001 (bulk, 1930-1995)
  - 1934 Corps member List, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Agricultural and Engineering Experiment Stations and Extension Services at Virginia Tech 1886-1934, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Athletic Notes, 1928, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Bulletins of VPI (4 copies), 1930-1939 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Cadet Life During The First Year of VAMC, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Chronology of Authorities Leading to the Establishment and Maintenance of the Reserve Officer's Training Corps at VPI & SU, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "Context", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Corps of Cadets Research, 1930-1972 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Early Radio at VPI, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - The First Ring Dance, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Fraternities at Virginia Tech, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - German Club, 1929, 1978, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - History of the YMCA at VPI, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Kappa Alpha Order, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Letters and Memorabilia From VPI Students, 1882-1937 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Military Staff 1872-1947, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous VPI Publications, 1939-2001 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - "Moonlight and VPI" Music and Words, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Newspaper Articles (copies and microfilm), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Newspaper Clippings Regarding VPI, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - The Origins of the V.P.I. Cadet Band, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - "Regulations at VPI", 1930 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - "Smithfield News", 1997, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - "Tech Triumph", 1962-1994 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - VAMC Historical Data Book, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - VAMC Literary Societies at the College, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Virginia Tech Corps of Cadets Strategic Plan, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - VPI Administrator Correspondence 1926-1939 (copies), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - VPI History Notes and Drafts, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - VPI Maps, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - VPI Music, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - VPI Printing Plant, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - VPI Reminisces, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - War Memorial Chapel Refurbishment, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Series IV: Ephemera Research, 1938-2001
  - 1904 Manuevers at Manasses, Virginia, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "American Soldier", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Blacksburg Churches Research, 1953-1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Blacksburg Episcopal Church Drawings and Pamphlets, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Civil War Articles and Notes, 1938-1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Ephemera, 1986-1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ephemera Research Notes, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Genesis of the Huckleberry Railroad, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Historic Addresses Posters, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - History of the VA National Guard and 60th Coast Artillery, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Korean War, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Maps of Britain and Ireland, 1966-1969, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Maps of Scotland, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
  - Military Maps
    - Battle Maps from Europe, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Maps - Army, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Battle of Corunna (2 copies), 1809-01-16 (Folder 2)
    - Battle of Waterloo (3 copies), 1815-06-18 (Folder 2)
    - Battle of Balaclava (2 copies), 1854-10-25 (Folder 2)
    - Napoleon's Campaign in Europe (2 copies), n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Military Prints (oversize)
    - "Remember the River Raisin'!" (Folder 2)
    - The Mississippi Rifles (Folder 2)
    - Lafayette and the National Guard (Folder 2)
    - "…the whites of their eyes!" (Folder 2)
    - Military uniform calendars (Box 33)
  - Military Research, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - National Guard in Blacksburg Research, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Nuclear, Biological, Chemical, Attach "What to Do" Pamphlets, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Postcards and Stamps, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Publications A-C, 1961-1972 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    "The Bishop's Garden," n.d.
    Butler's Lives of the Saints (photocopy), n.d.
    "Ceremonial to be Observed at the Funeral of the Right and Honourable Sir Winston Leonard Spencer-Churchill," 1965
    "The Civil War: A Catalog of Books in the Army Library Pertinent to the Civil War (photocopy)," 1961
    "Christ's Hospital," n.d.
    "Coldstream Guards and the Blackwatch," 1970
    "Constitution and Canons of the Protestant Episcopal Church in the Diocese of Virginia," 1972
  - Publications E-L, 1970, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    "Edinburgh Military Tattoo," 1979
    "Historical Collections of Georgia (reprint)," n.d.
    "The Kings and Queens of Great Britain," 1970
    List of Field Officers, Regiments and Battalions in the Confederate States Army 1861-1865 (photocopy), n.d.
  - Publications M-O, 1970, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Memorandum relative to the General Officers Appointed by the President in the Armies of the Confederate States 1861-1865 (photocopy), n.d.
    A New Pocket Directory of Episcopal Churches in the U.S.A, 1970
    "The Old Guard: History of the Third Infantry," n.d.
    "Order of DeMolay Conclave," 1997
  - Publications R-Z, 1951-1972 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    A Record of Confederate Generals (photocopy), n.d.
    Records of Louisiana Confederate Soldiers and Louisiana Confederate Commands (photocopy), n.d.
    "Standing Operating Procedure for the Provisional Battalion Commander and His Staff," 1951
    "Tradition," 1969
    "The United States Army Band," 1972
  - Research Requests, 1978-1995 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Virginia Maps, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Series V: Bugles Echo Manuscripts, 1979-1986, n.d.
  - Expenses Connected with The Bugles Echo, 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Bugle's Echo notes, Volume 1 (Forward, Expenses, prior to 1872-1892) (Box 22, Folder 1-45)
  - The Bugle's Echo notes, Volume 1 (1892-1900) (Box 23, Folder 1-27)
  - Bugles Echo Notes (Vol 1 & 2), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bugles Echo Notes (Vol 4), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Bugle's Echo notes, Volume 2 (1900-1907) (Box 24, Folder 1-22)
  - The Bugle's Echo notes, Volume 2 (1907-1912) (Box 25, Folder 1-19)
  - The Bugle's Echo notes, Volume 3 (1912-1918) (Box 26, Folder 1-14)
  - The Bugle's Echo notes, Volume 3 (1918-1920) (Box 27, Folder 1-18)
  - The Bugle's Echo notes, Volume 4 (1920-1924) (Box 28, Folder 1-15)
  - The Bugle's Echo notes, Volume 4 (1923-1926) and Volume 5 (1926-1927) (Box 29, Folder 1-16)
  - Example Handwritten Manuscripts from Vol. 4, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 6-9)
  - The Bugle's Echo notes, Volume 5 (1927-1930) (Box 30, Folder 1-22)
  - The Bugle's Echo notes, Volume 5 (1931-1933) (Box 31, Folder 1-18)
  - The Bugle's Echo notes, Volume 6 (1933-1934) (Box 32, Folder 1-19)
  - Bugles Echo Notes - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
  - Floppy Disk Copies of Manuscripts (Box 6)
- Series VI: Research Files for Future Bugle's Echo, 1934-2004 (bulk, 1934-1989)
  - Research Files, 1934-1935 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Research Files, 1935-1936 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Research Files, 1936-1937 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Research Files (5 folders), 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 4-8)
  - Research Files (5 folders), 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 9-10, Box 13, Folder 1-3)
  - Research Files (5 folders), 1939-1940 (Box 13, Folder 4-8)
  - Research Files (6 folders), 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 9-12, Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Research Files (7 folders), 1941-1942 (Box 14, Folder 3-9)
  - Research Files (8 folders), 1942-1943 (Box 14, Folder 10-12, Box 15, Folder 1-5)
  - Research Files (5 folders), 1943-1944 (Box 15, Folder 6-10)
  - Research Files (4 folders), 1944-1945 (Box 15, Folder 11-13, Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Research Files (7 folders), 1945-1946 (Box 16, Folder 2-8)
  - Research Files (6 folders), 1946-1947 (Box 16, Folder 9-12, Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - Research Files (3 folders), 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 3-5)
  - Research Files (4 folders), 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 6-9)
  - Research Files (5 folders), 1949-1950 (Box 17, Folder 10-14)
  - Research Files (4 folders), 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 1-4)
  - Research Files (4 folders), 1951-1952 (Box 18, Folder 5-8)
  - Research Files (3 folders), 1952-1953 (Box 18, Folder 9-11)
  - Research Files (4 folders), 1953-1954 (Box 18, Folder 12-15)
  - Research Files, 1954-1955 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Research Files (4 folders), 1955-1956 (Box 19, Folder 2-5)
  - Research Files (3 folders), 1956-1957 (Box 19, Folder 6-8)
  - Research Files (3 folders), 1957-1958 (Box 19, Folder 9-11)
  - Research Files (3 folders), 1958-1959 (Box 19, Folder 12-14)
  - Research Files (4 folders), 1959-1960 (Box 19, Folder 15, Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - Research Files (3 folders), 1960-1961 (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
  - Research Files (3 folders), 1961-1962 (Box 20, Folder 7-9)
  - Research Files (2 folders), 1962-1963 (Box 20, Folder 10-11)
  - Research Files, 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Research Files, 1964-1965 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Research Files (2 folders), 1965-1966 (Box 20, Folder 14-15)
  - Research Files (2 folders), 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  - Research Files, 1967-1968 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Research Files, 1968-1969 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Research Files, 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 5)